Cyrus Nash papers, 1630-1837.
Congregational Library & Archives
Cyrus Nash papers, 1630-1837.
MS0932
Congregational Library & Archives
.44 Cubic Feet
(1 case)
Cyrus Nash was born on May 8th, 1750 in Abington, Mass. His parents were Luke and Nabby Nash. He worked as the parish clerk for the Abington Church. He recorded information about Abington and the surrounding area, including vital statistics, histories, and council reports. After falling from his roof, he was confined to his home for his last 45 years. While at home, he became fascinated in a vareity of topics and news that came his way, taking notes on what he could. He died on March 4th, 1850 at the age of 69. This collection contains records related to the town of Abington, such as vital statistics, monetary transactions, Ecclesiastical reports, genealogies and town histories. Also included are Nash's personal notes, observations and journals.
Nash, Cyrus, 1780-1850
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
No acquisition information is available for this collection.
Biographical Note
Cyrus Nash was born on May 8th, 1750 in Abington, Mass. His parents were Luke and Nabby Nash. He worked as the parish clerk for the Abington Church. He recorded information about Abington and the surrounding area, including vital statistics, histories, and council reports. After falling from his roof, he was confined to his home for his last 45 years. While at home, he became fascinated in a vareity of topics and news that came his way, taking notes on what he could. He died on March 4th, 1850 at the age of 69.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains records related to the town of Abington, such as vital statistics, monetary transactions, Ecclesiastical reports, genealogies and town histories. Also included are Nash's personal notes, observations and journals.
Arrangement
This collection is divided into three series. Records in each series are arranged chronologically by start where applicable.
Series 1: Related to the town of Abington, 1630-1837
Series 2: Personal records, 1758-1833
Series 3: Related to the town of Abington and personal records, 1830-1835
Related Materials
Additional records on Cyrus Nash can be found at the Dyer Memorial Library in Abington, Mass.
Bibliography
Waters, Henry F., New England historical and genealogical register. Samuel G. Drake: Boston, 1850. https://archive.org/details/newenglandhistor004wate/page/293/mode/1up.
Massachusetts -- History.; Vital statistics.; Diaries.; Finance.; Nash, Cyrus, 1780-1850; Abington (Mass.) -- History.
- Related to the town of Abington, 1630 1837; 1630-1837; 17 Files
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records from Cyrus Nash that deal with the town of Abington, such as vital statistics, monetary transactions, Ecclesiastical reports, genealogies and town histories.
  - An index to the history of the first settlers in Abington, 1630 1830; 1630-1830 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vital statistics in Abington, 1667 1837; 1667-1837 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Birth records in Abington, 1694 1757; 1694-1757 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Vital statistics and notes on the Eclipse, 1726 1834; 1726-1834 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Copy of town records, 1731 1781; 1731-1781 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Articles of agreement for Abington mill, 1735-03-01 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Payments, 1736 1770; 1736-1770 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - First church and society of Abington records, 1770 1814; 1770-1814 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ecclesiastical council report, June 7, 1813 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ecclesiastical council report, 1820-07-28 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Monetary transactions, 1827 1831; 1827-1831 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Result of the council at Abington, 1830-01-05 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ecclesiastical council report, 1830-01 1830-02; January-February 1830 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Perish meetings, 1830 1831; 1830-1831 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Meeting notes, March 16 and 21 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Town histories and notes on sermons, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - History of Abington and genealogy, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Personal records, 1758 1833; 1758-1833; 10 Files
  This series contains records from Cyrus Nash's personal notes, observations and journals.
  - Observations and notes, 1758 1830; 1758-1830 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Written copies of newspaper articles, 1817 1833; 1817-1833 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Family history, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Journal, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Copy of Dr. Green's questions and counsel to professors, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Book binding and agricultural guides, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Notes on medicine, agriculture and population, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Notes on money, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Request to clean spoons, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Life of Swedenborg, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Related to the town of Abington and personal records, 1830 1835; 1830-1835; 3 Files
  This series contains items with information about both the town of Abington and Cyrus Nash's personal records.
  - Observations, notes and vital statistics, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Vital statistics and notes on religion, 1834 1835; 1834-1835 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Vital statistics and "How does a man become a universalist?", undated (Box 1, Folder 24)